Guide to the Sailors' Snug Harbor Image Collection MC.218
New York University Archives
Sailors' Snug Harbor Image Collection
1895-1905
New York University Archives
MC.218
7 Linear Feet in 16 boxes
The Sailors' Snug Harbor was created in 1801 as a charity for the support of aged sailors. The collection contains 98 glass plate negatives of property holdings of the Sailors' Snug Harbor within the area bounded by Fifth Avenue, 9th and 10th Streets, Fourth Avenue, Astor Place, 8th Street, University Place, and Washington Square North. The images date from the late 1800s, possibly into the early 1900s.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
Commissioned by and for Sailors' Snug Harbor, these images depict every building on the 21 acres of leasehold land owned by that charitable foundation throughout the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. Specifically, the Harbor's property covered most of the ten square blocks between Fifth and Fourth Avenues from Washington Square North and Waverly Place to Tenth Street. Of the buildings shown that survive today, most are owned by New York University.
Robert Richard Randall, son of wealthy merchant and entrepreneur Thomas Randall, allowed for the creation of Sailor's Snug Harbor in 1801 by bequeathing the majority of his estate, the Randall farm, for the purposes of establishing a support community to protect sailors. He intended this charity organization to serve aged sailors who had spent at least ten years at sea, five of which must have been spent sailing aboard an American vessel. In his will, Randall appointed prominent members of New York society, including Captain James Farquhar, DeWitt Clinton, Charles H. Marshal, and John Whetten (who would later become governor of what was to become the Sailors' Snug Harbor), to the board of trustees of this new organization.
It would become the responsibility of the trustees to construct a community for retired sailors who needed housing and medical support. They were given full management of the Randall farm, located in lower Manhattan. In 1823 the exponentially rising value of the property and changing nature of the surrounding neighborhood prompted discussions about the potential relocation of the Harbor. The income from leasing the land would provide significant funds for the charity. New York Governor Daniel Tompkins offered to procure a tract of land on the North Shore of Staten Island, of approximately 10 acres in size, for the development of a hospital and housing for the retired sailors.
Prior to construction of the new hospital, the trustees were engaged in litigation with a number of Randall's relations claiming to be legitimate heirs to the estate, most notably Bishop John Inglis, who came close to convincing the court to overturn the tenets of the original will.
The old Randall farm property was divided, and leases were auctioned. The profits derived from the leases were used to develop a retirement community on Staten Island where sailors were provided housing, meals, and medical care. The community functioned until 1972 when New York State Senator John Lindsay repurposed the land for a cultural center, and the Sailors' Snug Harbor foundation relocated to North Carolina.
Provenance
In the 1970s Sailors' Snug Harbor relocated from New York to North Carolina and began to divest itself of its properties in Manhattan and on Staten Island. The glass plate negatives that comprise this collection were removed from the Harbor's former headquarters on Greene Street and ended up at an auction house. The plates were purchased by Pageant Book and Print Shop, then on Fourth Avenue between Ninth and Tenth Streets. In 2005 the University Archives purchased the plates from the owner of Pageant's archives.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by approximate location of structures in the images, which is tracked on a paper key.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains 98 glass plate negative images of the property holdings of the Sailors' Snug Harbor. These buildings were found within the area bounded by Fifth Avenue, 9th and 10th Streets, Fourth Avenue, Astor Place, 8th Street, University Place, and Washington Square North.
It also includes prints for images 21-92 and a key identifying the locations of the buildings depicted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
New York University Archives purchased the collection from the owner of Pageant Book and Print Shop's archives in 2005.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must view digital surrogates of the glass plate negatives. The key and photographic prints (Box 15) may be viewed in the reading room.
Plate 15 is missing from the collection. Plates 17, 19, 27, and 59 are damaged.
Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Washington Square (New York, N.Y.); Sailors' Snug Harbor (Institution)
- Glass plate negatives, 1895-1905; 181762
  - Plate 1, 1895-1905; ssh_1; 181763; 11 x 14 glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 1)
    General
    Lot number: 746, 748, 750
    Street Address: 750 Broadway/1 Astor Place
    Number of Structures: 1
    Building Date(s): 1881-present
    Architect: Starkweather & Gibbs
    Business/Residence: Fleisher Bros.; Fecheimer Fishel Co.
    Extant/Demolished: Extant
    Comments: Corner lot; brickwork and terra-cotta
    Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.)
  - Plate 2, 1895-1905; ssh_2; 182944; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; One glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 2)
    Lot number: 11
    Street Address: 11 Astor Place
    Building Date(s):
    Architect: unknown
    Business/Residence: Sinclair House Restaurant
    Extant/Demolished:
    Comments: Building fronts both Astor Place and corner of B'way and 8th Street
  - Plate 3, 1895-1905; ssh_3; 183918; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; One glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 3)
    Lot #: 752, 754
    Architect: Unknown
    Building Date: c. 1860s
    Residence: Business/Sinclair House (Hotel)
    # od Structures: 1
    Street Address: 752-754 Broadway
  - Plate 4, 1895-1905; ssh_4; 183919; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; One glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 4)
    Lot #: 141, 143, 145
    Street Address: 141, 143, 145 East 8th Street
    # of Structures: 3
    Building Dates: c. 1830-40
    Comments: Former residences converted to businesses
    Business/Residence: No. 143 P. Mahony Basket Factory; No. 145 Germania Theatre Hotel and Restaurant
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for Wanamaker Store Annex in 1904 (D.H. Burnham & Co.)
  - Plate 5, 1895-1905; ssh_5; 183920; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; One glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 5)
    Lot # 135, 137, 139
    Street Address: 135, 137, 139 East 8th Street
    Business/Residence: No. 135 Ladies Silk Waists; No. 137 Printing, Fine Furs, No. 139 E.F. Langs
  - Plate 6, 1895-1905; ssh_6; 183921; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; One glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 6)
    Lot #: 756, 758, 760
    Street Address: 756, 758, 760 Broadway
    # of Structures 1
    Building Dates: c. 1885-1904
    Architects: Unknown
    Comments: Corner lot loft building with multiple businesses
    Business/Residence:
  - Plate 7, 1895-1905; ssh_7; 183922; 11x14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 1, Item 7)
    Lot #: 762, 764, 766
    Street Address: 762-766 Broadway
    # of Structures: 1
    Building Date: c. 1885-1904
    Comments: Mid-block 5-story loft building with multiple businesses
    Building/Residence: Schloss Bros. Company, S. Steinberg and Co., George N. Bliss and Co.
  - Plate 8, 1895-1905; ssh_8; 183923; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; oneglass plate negative (Box 2, Item 1)
    Lot #: 768, 770
    Business/Residence: Upper Floors part of original Wanamaker's Annex
    Building Dates: c. 1850-65; c. 1850-65
    # of Structures: 2
    Street Address: 768, 770 Broadway
  - Plate 9, 1895-1905; ssh_9; 183924; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 2, Item 2)
    Lot #: 74, 76, 78, 80, 82, 84
    Street Address: East 9th Street
    # of Structures: 5
    Building Dates:
    Comments:
    Building/Residence:
  - Plate 10, 1895-1905; ssh_10; 183925; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 2, Item 3)
    Lot #: 84, 86
    Building Dates: c. 1860s-1870s
    Business/Residence: Wanamaker's Annex
  - Plate 11, 1895-1905; ssh_11; 183926; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 2, Item 4)
    Lot #: 88, 90, 92
    Building Date: c. 1890
  - Plate 12, 1895-1905; ssh_12; 183927; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 2, Item 5)
    Lot #: 54, 56
    Street Address: Fourth Avenue
    Building Dates: c. 1880, 1890
  - Plate 13, 1895-1905; ssh_13; 183928; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 2, Item 6)
    Lot #: 52
    Building Dates: c. 1830
    Comments: Former residence converted to business
    Business/Residence: Charles Schwartz Trunks and Bags
  - Plate 14, 1895-1905; ssh_14; 183929; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 2, Item 7)
    Lot #:
    Street Address: Broadway
    Building Dates: 1862-1956
    Architect: John Kellum
    Comments: A.T. Stewart and Company, then Wanamaker's from 1896 (took over lease)
    Business/Residence: A.T. Stewart and Company
    Extant/Demolished: Razed in 1956 fire; 1960 white brick "Stewart House" apartment house on site today.
  - Plate 16, 1895-1905; ssh_16; 183931; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 1)
    Lot #: 76, 78; 61, 63, 65, 67, 69
    Street Address: Fourth Avenue; East 10th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1860s, c. 1860s
    Building/Residence: Multiple
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished? Today playground for Grace Church School
  - Plate 17, 1895-1905; ssh_17; 183932; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 16, Item 1)
    Lot #: 753, 755
    Street Address: 753-755 Broadway
    Building Dates: c. 1875
    Comments: Post Civil War corner lot loft building
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for Georgetown Plaza (1967) apartment building
  - Plate 18, 1895-1905; ssh_18; 183933; 11 x14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 2)
    Lot #: 757, 759
    Street Address: 757, 759 Broadway
    # of Structures: # 2
    Building Dates: c. 1870s
    Comments: Business Structures with later additions added on top
    Business/Residence: Multiple
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for The Lafayette (30 E. 9), 40 E. 9, & The Hamilton (60 E. 9th) in 1950
  - Plate 19, 1895-1905; ssh_19; 183934; 11 x 14 plate glass negative (Box 16, Item 2)
    Lot #: 741, 743, 745, 747
    Street Address: 741, 743-745, 747 Broadway
    Building Date: c. 1870s
    Comments: Post Civil War business structures
  - Plate 20, 1895-1905; ssh_20; 183935; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 3)
    Lot #: 302, 304, 306
    Street Address: 302-304, 306 Mercer Street
    Building Date: Unknown
  - Plate 21, 1895-1905; ssh_21; 183936; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 4)
    Lot #: 60, 62
    Street Address: 60, 62 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: Unknown
  - Plate 22, 1895-1905; ssh_22; 183937; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 5)
    Lot #: 64, 66
    Street Address: 64, 66 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1820s
  - Plate 23, 1895-1905; ssh_23; 183938; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 6)
    Lot #: 297, 299
    Street Address: 297-299 Mercer Street
    Building Dates: c. 1890s
    Comments: Commercial Loft Building (Fronts both Mercer and Greene Streets)
    Extant/Demolished: Exant (Residential Conversion)
    Business/Residence: Business
  - Plate 24, 1895-1905; ssh_24; 183939; one glass plate negative (Box 3, Item 7)
    Lot #: 258, 260
    Street AddresS: 258-260 Greene Street
    Building Date: c. 1890s
    Busines/Residence: Business
    Extant/Demolished: Exant (Residential Conversion, Ground Floor Business)
    11 x 14 glass plate negative
  - Plate 25, 1895-1905; ssh_25; 183940; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 1)
    Lot #: 262
    Street Address: 262-264 Greene Street
    # of Structures: c. 1830s
    Extant/Demolished: Exant (Used as administrative offices for SSH until approx. 1976)
  - Plate 26, 1895-1905; ssh_26; 183941; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 2)
    Lot #: 264, 266, 44, 46
    Street Address: 266 Greene Street, 44, 46 East 8th Street
  - Plate 27, 1895-1905; ssh_27; 183942; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 16, Item 3)
    Lot #: 48, 50
    Street Address: 48, 50 East 8th Street
    Comments: Commercial Loft Building
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished
  - Plate 28, 1895-1905; ssh_28; 183943; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 3)
    Lot #: 52, 54
    Street Address: 52, 54 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1830s, c.1880
    Comments: Former residence converted to business; Loft Building
    Business/Reside Business/Residence: Business
  - Plate 29, 1895-1905; ssh_29; 183944; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 4)
    Lot #: 56, 58
    Street Address: 56, 58 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1830s, c.1830s
  - Plate 30, 1895-1905; ssh_30; 183945; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 5)
    Lot #: 5, 7
    Street Address: 5, 7 University Place
    Building Dates: c. 1830s
    Comments: No. 5 former residence converted to business; No. 7 residence
    Business/Residence: Business, residence
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for aparment building in 1929 (Emory Roth, architect)
  - Plate 31, 1895-1905; ssh_31; 183946; 11 x 14 photo glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 6)
    Lot #: 9, 11, 13
    Street Address: 9-13 University Place
    3 of Structures: 1
    business/Residence: Business
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for NYU Weinstein Dormitory after 1955
  - Plate 32, 1895-1905; ssh_32; 183947; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 4, Item 7)
    Lot #: 15, 17, 19; 32, 32
    Street Address: 19 University Place
    Building Dates: 1895-1896
    Architect: Alfred Zucker
    Comments: Commercial Loft Building (Merck Building)
    Extant/Demolished: Extant (Used by NYU since ?)
  - Plate 33, 1895-1905; ssh_33; 183948; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 1)
    Lot #: 36, 38
    Lot #: 36, 38 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1830, c. 1870
    Comments: Former residence converted to loft building; Commercial building
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for 1930s Art Deco Studios
  - Plate 34, 1895-1905; ssh_34; 183949; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 2)
    Business/Residence: Commercial Loft Building (Merck Building) Business
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for NYU Weinstein Dormitory in 19?
  - Plate 35, 1895-1905; ssh_35; 183950; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 3)
    Lot #: 261, 263
    Street Address: 261 & 263 Greene Street
    Building Dates: c. 1830, c. 1860
  - Plate 36, 1895-1905; ssh_36; 183954; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 4)
    Lot #: 255, 257, 259
    Street Address: 255, 257, 259 Greene Street
    LBusiness/Residence: Business
  - Plate 37, 1895-1905; ssh_37; 183955; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 5)
    Lot #: 1, 2, 3
    Street Address: 1, 2, 3 Washington Square North
    Building Dates: 1831-33
    Comments: Former residences converted to NYU offices
    Extant/Demolished: Extant (Used by NYU since ? - varies per individual building)
  - Plate 38, 1895-1905; ssh_38; 183956; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 6)
    Lot #: 4, 5
    Street Address: 4, 5 Washington Square North
    Business/Residence: Residence
  - Plate 39, 1895-1905; ssh_39; 183957; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 5, Item 7)
    Lot #: 6, 7, 8
    Street Address: 6, 7, 8 Washington Square North
    Comments: Former residences converted to NYU offices/apartments
    Extant/Demolished: Extant (No. 6 owned by NYU since 1959; Nos. 7-13 faade only, 1939 residential apt. house)
  - Plate 40, 1895-1905; ssh_40; 183958; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 1)
    Lot #: 9, 10
    Street Address: 9, 10 Washington Square North
    Building/Residence: Residence
  - Plate 41, 1895-1905; ssh_41; 183959; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 2)
    Lot #: 11, 12, 13
    Street Address: 11, 12, 13 Washington Square North
  - Plate 42, 1895-1905; ssh_42; 183960; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 3)
    Lot #:Lot #: 1,3
    Street Address: 1, 3 Fifth Avenue
    Building Dates: c.1830s/40s
    Comments: Residences
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for 1 Fifth Avenue Apartment Building 1929; Helmle, Corbett, & Harisson
  - Plate 43, 1895-1905; ssh_43; 183962; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 4)
    Street Address: 5, 7 Fifth Avenue
    Building Dates: c.1830s
  - Plate 44, 1895-1905; ssh_44; 183963; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 5)
    Lot #: 4, 6, 8
    Street Address: 4, 6, 8 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: 1834-1836
    Extant/Demolished:: Extant. Single Family Residences converted remolded into apts 1916 (Harvey Wiley Corbett).
  - Plate 45, 1895-1905; ssh_45; 183964; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 6)
    Lot #: 10, 12, 14
    Street Address: 10, 12, 14 East 8th Street
    Extant/Demolished: Extant. Single Family Residences converted remolded into apts 1916 (Harvey Wiley Corbett)
  - Plate 46, 1895-1905; ssh_46; 183965; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 6, Item 7)
    Lot #: 16, 18, 20
    Street Address: 16, 18, 20 East 8th Street
  - Plate 47, 1895-1905; ssh_47; 183966; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 1)
    Lot #: 22, 24, 26
    Street Address: 22, 24, 26 East 8th Street
  - Plate 48, 1895-1905; ssh_48; 183967; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 2)
    Lot #: 20, 22
    Street Address: 20, 22 University Place
    Business/Residence: Business; Residence
    Extant/Demolished: Demolished for The Brevoort Apartments (1955) and Brevoort East Apartments (1965)
  - Plate 49, 1895-1905; ssh_49; 183968; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 3)
    Lot #: 17, 19, 21
    Street Address: 17, 19, 21 East 8th Street
    Comments: Nos. 17 & 21 Residences; No. 19 Part commercial & residential
  - Plate 50, 1895-1905; ssh_50; 183969; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 4)
    Lot #: 11, 13, 15
    Street Address: 11, 13, 15 East 8th Street
    Comments: No. 11 commercial; Nos. 13 & 15 residential
    Business/Residential:
  - Plate 51, 1895-1905; ssh_51; 183972; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 5)
    Lot #: 5, 7, 9
    Street Address: 6, 7, 9 East 8th Street
    Comments: All former residences converted to commercial (ground & parlor levels)
  - Plate 52, 1895-1905; ssh_52; 183971; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 6)
    Street Address: Fifth Avenue
    Comments: 3 former residences cobbled together to create hotel 1852-54
    Business/Residence: Commercial (Hotel)
  - Plate 53, 1895-1905; ssh_53; 183973; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 7, Item 7)
    Lot #: 15, 17
    Street Address: 15, 17 Fifth Avenue
    Comments: Former residences incorporated into Brevoort Hotel?
    Building Dates: c. 1840s?
    Business/Residence: Commercial (Hotel)?
  - Plate 54, 1895-1905; ssh_54; 183974; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 1)
    Street Address: 4, 6, 8 East 9th Street
    Comments: No. 4 former residence turned commercial, Nos. 6-8 residential
  - Plate 55, 1895-1905; ssh_55; 183975; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 2)
  - Plate 56, 1895-1905; ssh_56; 183976; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 3)
    Lot #: 42
    Street Address: 42 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1860s?
    Comments: commercial
    Business/Residential: Commercial
  - Plate 57, 1895-1905; ssh_57; 183977; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 4)
    Lot #: 24, 26, 28, 30, 32, 34
    Street Address: 24-24 University Place
    Building Dates: c. 1880s
    Comments: Commercial
    Business/Residence: Commercial
  - Plate 58, 1895-1905; ssh_58; 183978; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 5)
    Lot #: 749, 751
    Street Address: 749, 751 Broadway
    Building Dates: post 1865
  - Plate 59, 1895-1905; ssh_59; 183979; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 16, Item 4)
    Lot #: 63, 65, 67
    Street Address: 63, 65, 67 East 8th Street
  - Plate 60, 1895-1905; ssh_60; 183980; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 6)
    Lot #: 69, 71, 73
    Street Address: 69, 71, 73 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: c. 1885
    Comments: commercial loft building
  - Plate 61, 1895-1905; ssh_61; 183981; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 8, Item 7)
    Lot #: 57, 59, 61
    Street Address: 57, 59, 61 East 8th Street
    Building Dates: post 1865; c.1830s
    Comments: nos. 59 & 61 former residences converted to commercial
    Extent/Demolished: Demolished for The Lafayette (30 E. 9), 40 E. 9, & The Hamilton (60 E. 9th) in 1950
  - Plate 62, 1895-1905; ssh_62; 183982; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 1)
    Lot #: 51, 53, 55
    Street Address: 51, 53, 55 East 8th Street
  - Plate 63, 1895-1905; ssh_63; 183983; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 2)
    Lot #: 45, 47, 49
    Street Address: 45, 47, 49 East 8th Street
    Architect:Unknown Unknown
  - Plate 64, 1895-1905; ssh_64; 183984; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 3)
    Street Address:
  - Plate 65, 1895-1905; ssh_65; 183985; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 4)
  - Plate 66, 1895-1905; ssh_66; 183986; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 5)
    Lot #: 21, 23, 25, 27
    Street Address: 21 & 27? University Place
    Comments: former residences converted to commercial
  - Plate 67, 1895-1905; ssh_67; 183987; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 6)
    Lot #: 29, 31, 33
    Street Address: 29-33 University Place
    Business/Residence: Commercial (hotel)
  - Plate 68, 1895-1905; ssh_68; 183988; 11 x 14 plate glass negative; one glass plate negative (Box 9, Item 7)
    Lot #: 28, 30, 32
    Street Address: 28, 30, 32 East 9th Street
    Comments: Nos. 28 & 30 commercial; No. 32 residential
  - Plate 69, 1895-1905; ssh_69; 183997; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 10, Item 1)
    Lot #: 34, 36
    Street Address: 34, 36 East 9th Street
  - Plate 70, 1895-1905; ssh_70; 183998; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 10, Item 2)
    Lot #: 38, 40
    Street Address: 38, 40 East 9th Street
  - Plate 71, 1895-1905; ssh_71; 183999; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 10, Item 3)
    Lot #: 42, 44
    Street Address: 42, 44 East 9th Street
  - Plate 72, 1895-1905; ssh_72; 184000; one glass plate negative (Box 10, Item 4)
    Lot #: 46, 48
    Street Address: 46, 48 East 9th Street
  - Plate 73, 1895-1905; ssh_73; 184001; 11 x 14 glass plate negative; one glass plate negative (Box 10, Item 5)
    Lot #: 50, 52
    Street Address: 50, 52 East 9th Street